And so the world has fundamentally
changed. These are going to be really
important in the coming years. Well,
Taiwan doesn't just build supercomputers
for the world. Today, I'm very happy to
announce that we're also building AI for
Taiwan. I know that right now when we
say there's an intelligence
infrastructure, it makes no sense. But I
promise you in 10 years time, you will
look back and you will realize that AI
has now integrated into everything. The
modern computer is an entire data
center. The data center is a unit of
computing. No longer just a PC, no
longer just a server. The entire data
center, human or robot, it is likely to
be the next multi- trillion dollar
industry. Say it with me. The more you
buy, the more you make. But just please
buy something from
me. I'm very pleased to announce that
Nvidia
Constellation will be at Beto Shilling.
[Applause]
And I have
some surprises for you. Things that you
probably wouldn't have guessed.
GeForce Rest of Asia Pacific.
GTC AI
lighting AI.
[Music]
Enjoy. Hello,
Taiwan. It's great to be here. My
parents are also in the
audience. They're up there.
[Applause]
Nvidia has been coming to Taiwan for
over 30 years. This is the home of many
of our
treasured partners and dear
friends. Over the years, you have seen
Nvidia grow up and seen us
accomplished many exciting things and
have been partnered with me all along
the way.
Today we're going to talk
about where we
are in the industry, where we're going
to
go, announce some new products, exciting
new products and surprising products
that open new markets for
us, creates new markets, new growth.
We're going to talk
about great partners and how we're going
to develop this ecosystem
together. As you know, we are at the
epicenter of the computer
ecosystem, one of the most important
industries of the
world. And so it stands to
reason when new markets has to be
created, we have to create it starting
here.
at the center of the computer
ecosystem. And I have
some surprises for
you, things that you probably wouldn't
have
guessed. And then of course, I promise
I'll talk about
AI and we'll talk about
robotics. The NVIDIA
story is the reinvention of the computer
industry.
In fact, the NVIDIA story is also the
reinvention of our
company. As I said, I was been coming
here for 30
years. Many of you have been through
many of my
keynotes. Some of you, all of
them. And just as you reflect on the
conversation, the things we talked about
in the last 30 years, how dramatic we
changed. We started out as a chip
company with a goal of creating a new
computing
platform and in
2006 we
introduced
CUDA which has revolutionized how
computing is done.
In 2016, 10 years later, we realized
that a new computing approach has
arrived. And this new computing
approach requires a reinvention of every
single layer of the technology stack.
The processor is new, the software stack
is new. It stands to reason the system
is new. And so we invented a new system.
A new system that on the day I announced
it at GTC
2006, no one understood what I was
talking about and nobody gave me a
PO. That system was called
DGX1.
DGX1. I donated the first one to a
nonprofit company called
OpenAI and it started the AI
revolution. Years later, we realized
that in fact this new way of doing
software which is now called artificial
intelligence is unlike traditional ways
of running software. Whereas many
applications ran
on a few
processors in a large data center. We
call that hypers
scale. This new type of
application
requires many processors working
together serving queries for millions of
people and that data center would be
architected fundamentally different. We
realized there were two types of
networks. one for north south because
you still have to control the storage.
You still have to have a control plane.
You still have to connect to the
outside. But the most important network
was going to be east
west. The computers talking to each
other to try to solve a problem.
We recognized the most the best
networking company in east west traffic
for high performance computing largecale
distributed processing. A company that
was very dear to our company and very
close to our heart a company called
Melanox. And we bought them five years
ago
2019. We converted an entire data center
into one computing unit. And you heard
me say
before, the modern computer is an entire
data center. The data center is a unit
of computing. No longer just a PC, no
longer just a server. The entire data
center is running one job. And the
operating system would
change. Nvidia's data center journey is
now very well
known. Over the last three years, you've
seen some of the ideas that we're
shaping and how we are starting to see
our company
differently. No company in history,
surely no technology company in history
has ever revealed a road map for five
years at a
time. No one would tell you what is
coming
next. They keep it as a secret,
extremely confidential.
However, we realized that Nvidia is not
a technology company only
anymore. In fact, we are an essential
infrastructure company. And how can you
plan your
infrastructure, your land, your shell,
your power, your electricity, all of the
necessary financing around all over the
world? How would you possibly do that if
you didn't understand what I was going
to
make? And so we described our company's
roadmap in fair detail. Enough detail
that everybody in the world can go off
and start building data
centers. We realize now we are an AI
infrastructure
company. An infrastructure company
that's essential all around the world.
Every region, every industry, every
company will build these
infrastructures. And what are these
infrastructure?
These infrastructure in
fact not unlike the first industrial
revolution when people realized GE
Westinghouse Seammens realized that
there was a new type of technology
called electricity and new
infrastructure has to be built all
around the world and these
infrastructure became essential part of
social infrastructure that
infrastructure is now called
electricity.
Years later, this is during all of our
generation, we realized there was a new
type of infrastructure. And this new
infrastructure was very conceptual, very
hard to understand. And this
infrastructure called
information. This information
infrastructure the first time it was
described make no sense to anybody. But
we now realized it is the internet. And
every internet is everywhere and
everything is connected to it.
Well, there's a new infrastructure. Now,
this new infrastructure is built on top
of the first two. And this new
infrastructure is an infrastructure of
intelligence. I know that right now when
we say there's an intelligence
infrastructure, it makes no sense. But I
promise you in 10 years time, you will
look back and you will realize that AI
has now integrated into everything. And
in fact we need AI everywhere and every
region, every industry, every country,
every company all needs AI. AI has now
part of infrastructure. And this
infrastructure just like the internet,
just like electricity needs
factories. And these factories are
essentially what we build today. They're
not data centers of the past. a1
trillion dollar industry providing
information and storage supporting all
of our ERP systems and our employees.
It's that's a data center a data center
of the past. This
is similar in the sense that it came
from the same industry. It came from all
of us but it's going to emerge as
something completely different
completely separated from the world's
data center. And these AI data centers,
if you will, are improperly described.
They are in fact AI factories. You apply
energy to it and it produces something
incredibly valuable. And these things
are called tokens to the point where
companies are starting to talk about how
many tokens they produced last quarter
and how many tokens they produced last
month. Very soon we will be talking
about how many tokens we produce every
hour just as every single factory does.
And so the world has fundamentally
changed. We went from a company on the
day that we started our
company. I was trying to figure out how
big our opportunity was in 1993 and I
came to the conclusion Nvidia's business
opportunity was enormous.
$300 million.
We're going to be rich.
$300 million chip
industry to a data center opportunity
that represents about a trillion dollars
to now an AI factory and AI
infrastructure industry that will be
measured in trillions of
dollars. And this is the exciting future
that we're
undertaking. Now, at its
core, everything we do is founded on
several important technologies. Of
course, I talk about accelerated
computing a great deal. I talk about AI
a great deal. What makes Nvidia really
special is the fusion of these
capabilities and very specially very
especially the algorithms, the
libraries, what we call the CUDA X
libraries. We're talking about libraries
all the time. And in fact, we're the
only technology company in the world
that talks about libraries
non-stop. And the reason for that is
because libraries is at the core of
everything that we do. You know, when
you're CEO, you have many
children. And and GeForce brought us
here. And now all of our keynotes is 90%
not
GeForce. But it's not because we don't
love GeForce.
GeForce RTX 50 series just had its most
successful launch ever, the fastest
launch in our history, and PC gaming is
now 30 years old. So that tells you
something about how incredible GeForce
is. Let's talk about
libraries. At the core, of course,
everything starts with CUDA. And by
making CUDA as as uh performant as
possible, as pervasive as possible, so
that the install base is all over the
world. The more
libraries, more amazing things are done,
better applications, more benefits to
users, they buy more computers. The more
computers, more CUDA. That feedback path
is vitally important. So the the
libraries
themselves is what makes it possible for
us one domain of application after
another domain of science after another
domain of physics to be able to
accelerate those applications. GPUs
could be used for pre-processing and
post-processing for error correction for
control. And so in the future I predict
that all supercomputers will have
quantum accelerators all have quantum
QPUs connected to it. And so a
supercomputer would be a QPU with QPUs
and GPUs and some CPUs and that would be
the representation of a modern computer.
Generative AI gave us oneshot AI. You
give a text and it gives you text back.
You have now agentic AI. This agentic AI
just does something that I've just
described all of us do. We take we're
given a goal. We break it down step by
step. We reason about what to do. what's
the best way to do it? We consider its
consequences and then we start executing
the plan. The plan might include doing
some research, might include doing some
work as using some tools. It might
include reaching out to another AI agent
to collaborate with it. Agentic
AI is basically understand, think, and
act. Well, understand, think, and act is
the robotics loop. Agentic AI is
basically a robot in a digital form.
These are going to be really important
in the coming years. We're seeing
enormous progress in this area. The next
wave beyond that is physical AI. To be
able to reason about these physical
things is really essential to the next
era of AI. We call that physical AI. So
what used to be oneshot AI is now going
to be thinking AI, reasoning AI,
inference time scaling AI and that's
going to take a lot more computation.
And so we created a new system called
Grace Blackwell. Grace Blackwell does
several things. It has the ability to
scale up. Scale up means to turn what is
a computer into a giant computer. scale
out is to take a computer and connect
many of them together and let the work
be done in many different computers. In
Q3 of this year, just as I promised,
every single year, we will increase the
performance of our platform every single
year like Rhythm and this this year in
Q3, we'll upgrade to Grace Blackwell
GB300. The GB300 will increase the is
the same architecture.
Same architecture, same physical
footprint, same electrical, mechanicals,
but the chips inside have been upgraded.
It has upgraded with a new Blackwell
chip is now one and a half times more
inference performance, has one and a
half times more HBM memory, and it has
two times more networking. And so the
overall system performance is higher.
There's only a limit to how fast you can
make chips and how big you can make
chips. In the case of Blackwell, we even
connected two chips together to make it
possible. TSMC worked with us to invent
a new co-ass process called cos l that
made it possible for us to create these
giant chips. But still we want chips way
bigger than that. And so we had to
create what is called MVLink. This is
the world's fastest switch. This MVL
link here right here is 7.2 terabytes
per second. Nine of these go into that
rack. And that
nine, those nine switches are connected
by this miracle. This is um quite
heavy. That's because I'm quite strong.
I made it I made it look so light, but
this is almost this 70 pounds.
We now have the ability to disagregate
the
GPUs out of one motherboard essentially
across an entire rack. And so that
entire rack is one motherboard. That's
the miracle completely disagregated. And
now the GPU performance is incredible.
The amount of memory is incredible. The
networking bandwidth is incredible. And
now we can really scale these out. Once
we scale it up, then we can scale it out
into large systems. And notice almost
everything Nvidia builds are gigantic.
But really in the end we're not building
data centers. We're building AI
factories. And this is the XAI Colossus
factory. This is
Stargate. 4 million square feet. 4
million square feet. One gigawatt. And
so just think about this factory here.
This one gigawatt factory. This one
gigawatt factory is probably going to be
about, you know, 60 to 80 billion
dollars. Out of that 60 to80 billion
dollars, the electronics, the computing
part of it, these systems are 4050
billion dollars of it. And so these are
gigantic factory
investments. The reason why people build
factories is because, say it with me,
the more you buy, the more you
make. That's what factories do.
[Music]
We couldn't be
prouder of what we've achieved together.
Thank you, Taiwan.
[Music]
Thank
you. Thank you. That was pretty
incredible, right? But that was
you. That was you. Thank
you. Well,
Taiwan doesn't
just build supercomputers for the world.
Today I'm very happy to
announce that we're also building AI for
Taiwan. And so today we're announcing
that Foxcon,
Taiwan, the Taiwanese government,
Nvidia, TSMC, we're going to build the
first giant AI supercomputer here for
the AI infrastructure and the AI
ecosystem of Taiwan. And so today we're
announcing the MVLink Fusion. This
incredible body of work now becomes
flexible and open for everybody to
integrate into. And so your AI
infrastructure could have some Nvidia, a
lot of yours, a lot of yours, you know,
and and uh a lot of CPUs, a lot of AS6,
maybe a lot of NVIDIA GPUs as well. And
so in any case, you have the benefit of
using the MVLink infrastructure and the
MVLink ecosystem that's and it's
connected perfectly to Spectrum
X and all of that you know is industrial
strength and has the benefit of an
enormous ecosystem of industrial
partners who have already made it
possible. Now let me talk to you about
some new product categories. As you know
I've shown you a couple of different
computers.
This new computer we call DGX Spark is
in full production. We'll be ready, will
be available shortly, probably in a few
weeks, but you would just like to have
your own basically your own AI cloud
sitting right next to you. And it's
always on, always waiting for you. This
is
DGX1. This is one
pedlops and 128
gigabytes. Of course, this is 128
gigabytes of HBM memory and this is 128
gigabytes of
LPDDR5X. The performance is in fact
quite similar. But what's most important
is that the work that you could do you
could work on this is the same work you
could do here. One thing for
sure, everybody can have one for
Christmas.
If that one isn't big enough for you,
and this is going to be your own
personal
DGX
supercomput, this computer is the most
performance you can possibly get out of
a wall socket. You could put this in
your
kitchen, but just
barely. If you put this in your kitchen
and then somebody runs the microwave, I
think this is the limit of what you can
get out of a wall outlet. And this is a
DGX station, a one trillion parameter
model is going to run wonderfully on
this machine. And the new
capability for enterprise is agentic AI.
basically
digital marketing campaign manager, a
digital researcher, a digital software
engineer, digital customer service,
digital chip designer, digital supply
chain
manager, digital versions, AI versions
of all of the work that we used to do.
And as I mentioned
earlier, Agentic AI has the ability to
reason, use tools, work with other AIs.
So in a lot of
ways these are digital workers. They're
digital
employees. The world has a shortage of
labor. We have a shortage of workers by
2030 by about 30 to 50 million shortage.
It's actually limit limiting the world's
ability to grow. And so now we have
these digital agents that can work with
us. 100% of NVIDIA software engineers
now have digital agents working with
them so that they can help them assist
them in developing better code and more
productively. And so in the future,
you're going to have this layer, that's
our vision. You're going to have a layer
of agentic AIs, AI agents. And so what's
going to happen to the world? What's
going to happen to enterprise? Whereas
we have HR for human workers, we're
going to have it becoming the HR of
digital workers. for today's IT
industry, today's IT workers to be able
to
manage, improve, evaluate a whole family
of AI agents that are working inside
their company. And so that's the vision
of what we want to build. This is the
brand new RTX Pro RTX Pro Enterprise and
Omniverse server. Omniverse runs on here
perfectly. But in addition to that, in
addition to that, this is the
computer for enterprise AI
agents. Those AI agents could be only
text. Those AI agents could also be
computer
graphics, little TJs, you know, coming
to you, little toy Jensen's coming to
see you, you know, helping you do work.
And so those AI agents could be either
in text form, it could be in graphics
form, it could be in video form. All of
those workloads work on this system. The
compute platform is different, the
storage platform is different. And the
reason for that is because humans query
structured databases like SQL. But AI
wants to query unstructured data. They
want semantic. They want meaning. And so
we have to create a new type of storage
platform is because you need the system
to embed find the meaning in the data in
the in the unstructured data in the raw
data. You have to index you have to do
the search and you do the ranking. So
that process is very compute intensive
and so most storage servers in the
future will have a compute a GPU
computing node in front of it.
So agent AIS agentic AIs AI agents a lot
of different ways to say it agents are
essentially digital robots re reason for
that is because a robot perceives
understands and plans and that's
essentially what agents do but we would
like to build also physical robots and
these physical robots first it starts
with the ability to learn to be a robot
we're working on several things to help
the robotics industry Now, you know that
we've been working in in uh autonomous
systems for some time. Our self-driving
car basically has three systems. There's
the system for creating the AI model,
and that's GB200, GB300. It's going to
be used for that, training the AI model.
Then you have Omniverse for simulating
the AI model. And then when you're done
with that AI model, you put that model,
the AI into the self-driving car. Okay.
This year we're deploying Mercedes
around the world our self-driving car
stack end to end stack. We want to make
sure that we provide our technology in a
way that makes it as easy as possible
for everybody to integrate NVS
technology. You know, like I said, I
love it if you buy everything from me,
but just please buy something from
me. Very practical. And so today we're
announcing that Isaac Groot
N1.5 is now open sourced and it's open
to the world to use. It's been
downloaded 6,000 times already. But
human or robot it is likely to be the
next multi- trillion dollar industry and
the technology innovation incredibly
fast and the consumption of computing
and data centers enormous. But this is
one of those applications that needs
three computers. One computer is an AI
for learning. One computer is a
simulation engine where the AI could
learn how to be a robot in a in a
virtual environment and then also the
deployment of it. Everything that moves
will be
robotic. As we put these robots into the
factories, remember the factories are
also
robotic. Today's factories are so
incredibly complex. This is the Nvidia
AI factory in a digital twin.
Gong is a digital twin. They made
Gausong a digital
twin. There are already hundreds of
thousands of buildings, millions of
miles of roads. And so, yes, Gausing is
a digital twin. It stands to reason that
Taiwan at the center of the most
advanced
industry, the epicenter where AI and
robotics is going to come from. It
stands to reason that this is an
extraordinary opportunity for Taiwan. As
you know, we have been growing and all
of our partnerships with
you, have been growing. The number of
engineers we have here in Taiwan have
been
growing. And so, we are growing beyond
the limits of our current office. And so
I'm going to build them a brand new
Nvidia Taiwan office and it's called
Nvidia Constellation. I'm very pleased
to announce that Nvidia
Constellation will be at Beto
[Applause]
Shiling. We are in fact creating a whole
new industry. This whole new
industry is going to expose us to giant
opportunities ahead. I look forward to
partnering with all of you on building
AI factories, agents for enterprises,
robots, all of you amazing partners,
building the ecosystem with us around
one architecture. And so I want to thank
all of you for coming today. Have a
great Computex everybody.
[Applause]